

Patrick Hart (he/him) Atlanta, GA | 404-345-0396 | pathart612@gmail.com LinkedIn | GitHub | Medium

Software Developer

Working proficiency in Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, and React programming with a background in commercial photography. Possess strong skills in project design and troubleshooting that help creative companies develop novel solutions. While in high school and college I worked as an automotive mechanic, and later as a bike mechanic. I have a long history with diagnostics, troubleshooting, and repair/modifications. I like to build and fix things!

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, TypeScript, Nest.js, React, Git, Python, SQLite, PostgreSQL HTML, CSS

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Research Link - Github | Demo

An app to connect scientific research organizations with study participants.

- Utilized multiple many-to-many relationships to allow participants to apply for a clinical trial and enable organizations to enroll participants based on their applications.
- Implemented custom routes to retrieve data from my rails backend to display in html tables on a React frontend.
- Included sorting functionality on a table to arrange entries alphanumerically by column heading.
- Designed frontend components to dynamically generate stateful forms based on the number of questions in an array stored on the backend.
- Developed a clean aesthetic for the frontend with all custom CSS and HTML

Exercise Tracker - GitHub

A web app to log running and cycling activities with a social component.

- Built a PostrgreSQL backend on Rails to manage full CRUD capabilities for a many-to-many relationship between models
- Setup user authentication and authorization with bcrypt
- Designed a React front end for the client views
- Populated the database with a dynamic seeds file.

EXPERIENCE

Nonprofit Circle Remote

Volunteer Backend Developer | GitHub

09/2022 - Present

- Contributing to an open source project working with an asynchronous agile team
- Developing a Nest.js server-side app in TypeScript on Postgres
- Building additional backend features

Case-MateAtlanta, GAProduct Photographer06/2020 - 07/2021

- Managed a high-volume, on-site studio to produce and maintain a database with thousands of images
 - Functioned as a member of a coordinated creative team under tight deadlines with evolving deliverables
 - Designed a workflow for consistent results and built Photoshop actions to automate and speed production
 - Collaborated with CAD engineers on CG renderings for photo-compositing when product samples were not available
 - Produced nearly 1000 images seasonally for new Apple and Samsung phone model releases. These images were produced for the Case-Mate website and sales partnerships including AT&T, Verizon, Amazon, etc.

Pat Hart Photo LLC Atlanta, GA

Freelance Photographer & Digital Tech | pathartphoto.com

01/2014 - 02/2022

- Delivered creative assets to a large range of clients while working, both individually and with a variety of crews
- Adapted quickly to unforeseen challenges and managed client expectations
- Developed an excellent reputation for quality and customer service that grew my business and maximized client retention

EDUCATION

Flatiron School

New York, NY

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, and React

04/2022 - 07/2022

Emory UniversityAtlanta, GA
Bachelor of Arts. Economics | Visual Arts
08/2008 - 05/2013